Herbert A. Philbrick Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1849-1997 (Box 28-221)
  - Duncan, Terence J., 1958
  - Dungey, John K., 1956-1960, undated
  - “D” miscellaneous, 1951-1977, 1986, undated, (2 folders)
  - Earl, Elliott, 1951
  - Earth Day, 1970
  - East Prussia, 1966, undated
  - Eastland, James O., 1956-1959, 1977, undated
  - Eaton, Cyrus S., 1955-1972, undated
  - Ecology, 1970-1971 (Box 91)
  - Economic warfare, 1962-1965
  - Economics, 1951-1956, 1962-1979, 1987, undated, (3 folders)
  - Edmund Burke Society, 1970-1971, undated
  - Education, 1955-1976, 1990, undated
  - Edwards, Lee, 1966-1973, undated
  - Edwards, Violet, 1953, undated
  - Eikenberry, Helen, 1950, 1956-1957, undated
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1959-1972, undated
  - El Salvador, 1987-1990, undated
  - Elections, 1957-1958, 1967-1973, undated (Box 92)
  - Elks, fraternal order, 1964-1966, undated
  - Ellsberg, Daniel, 1971-1974, undated
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1952-1964, undated
  - Emergency Committee for Disaster Relief to Cuba, 1963-1964
  - Emergency Detention Act of 1950, 1970
  - Emmerson, John Kenneth, 1951, 1957, undated
  - Episcopal Church, 1953-1965, 1972, undated
  - Epps, William Burton, 1964-1967
  - Equal Rights Amendment (ERA), 1970-1975
  - Ernst, Morris L., 1956-1957, 1965-1972
  - Erteszek, Jan, 1957-1958, undated
  - Estonia, 1956-1957, undated
  - Eternity, 1960-1961
  - Ethical Culture societies, 1950-1955, 1965-1966
  - Europe, 1955-1968, 1975-1978, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 93)
  - Evans, M. Stanton (Stan), 1959-1960, 1966-1971
  - Evans, Rowland, and Robert Novak, 1964-1969, 1987-1990
  - Evans, Viola C., 1958, 1967
  - Evolution, 1965-1966, 1972, undated
  - Expellee Press Service (EPS), 1967-1969
  - Extremists, 1964-1967, undated
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1947-1981, 1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Fabian, Bela, 1951-1958, 1964, undated
  - Facts Forum, 1952-1956, undated, (3 folders)
  - Fair Play for Cuba Committee, 1961-1963
  - Fairbank, John K., 1966, 1972, undated (Box 94)
  - Falk Corp., 1958-1960, undated
  - Fallout, 1955-1962, undated
  - Families Opposing Revolutionary Donations (FORD), 1969-1970, undated
  - Farmers Liberty League, 1958-1960, undated
  - Fast, Howard, 1949-1957, 1965, 1989, undated
  - FCI, Features and News from Behind the Iron Curtain, 1957-1969, undated, (4 folders)
  - Feder, Don, 1985-1993, undated
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) See also Containers 8-9, same heading
    - Correspondence and memoranda
      - 1951-1959, (3 folders)
      - 1960-1971, 1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1949-1972, undated, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1958-1976, 1992, undated, (2 folders)
    - Press clippings, 1951, 1958-1988, undated
    - Printed matter, 1947, 1957-1975, undated, (3 folders) (Box 96)
  - Federal Communications Commission (FCC), 1959-1971, undated
  - Federal Reserve System, 1963, undated
  - Federal Trade Commission (FTC), 1975, undated
  - Federation of American Scientists, 1957-1958, undated
  - Fellow travelers, 1949, 1962, undated
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1949-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 97)
  - Field, Noel, 1949-1954, 1970, undated
  - Fiftieth anniversary of the Bolshevik Revolution, 1967-1968, undated, (6 folders)
  - Fighting Homefolks of Fighting Men, 1961-1964
  - Figuly, Ron, 1979-1983, undated
  - Fineberg, S. Andhil, 1953-1957, undated (Box 98)
  - Finland, 1966-1970, 1988, undated
  - First Baptist Church, Wakefield, Mass., 1948-1958, undated
  - Flag of the United States, 1955, 1962-1966, 1990, undated
  - Fleming, D. F., 1957-1962
  - Flemming, Arthur S., 1959-1966
  - Fish, Robert, 1960, 1969-1971, 1979
  - Fletcher, Martha, 1947-1954, 1960
  - Fletcher's Paint Works, 1977-1979, undated
  - Florida Coalition of Patriotic Societies, 1961-1967
  - Fluoridation, 1950-1970, undated, (5 folders) (Box 99)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1951, 1964, undated
  - Fonda, Jane, 1970-1984, undated
  - “Fool's Paradise,” 1967, 1989-1990
  - Forced repatriation, 1956-1957, undated
  - Ford Foundation, 1955-1957, 1968-1977, undated, (3 folders)
  - Ford, Gerald R., 1965, 1975-1977 (Box 100)
  - Foreign aid, 1957-1972, undated
  - Foreign exchange programs, 1958-1962, 1989, undated, (3 folders)
  - Foreign policy, 1931, 1959-1972, undated
  - Fortas, Abe, 1963-1969, undated, (2 folders)
  - Foster, Carol H., 1958-1960
  - Foster, William Z., 1948-1949, 1957-1960, 1967-1969, undated
  - Foundation for Economic Education, 1952-1970, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 101)
  - Foundation for Religious Action in the Social and Civil Order, 1952-1958, 1964-1969, 1984-1989, undated
  - Foundation to Defeat Communism, 1955, 1962, undated
  - Foundations, 1955, 1968-1970, 1977, undated
  - Four Continent Book Corp., 1953-1958, undated
  - Fox, Revill J., 1953-1970, undated
  - France, 1956, 1963-1970, 1987, (2 folders)
  - Frawley, Patrick, 1966-1970
  - Fredericks, Carleton, 1956-1957
  - Free Europe Committee, 1954-1958, undated
  - Free Men Speak, 1955-1957, undated (Box 102)
  - Free society, 1965
  - Freedom Academy, 1954-1966, undated, (4 folders)
  - Freedom Agenda, 1947, 1954-1956, undated
  - Freedom Center, 1961-1966, undated
  - Freedom Commission Act, 1959
  - Freedom fighters, 1962-1963, undated
  - Freedom in Action, 1958-1963
  - Freedom Leadership Foundation, 1969-1982, (2 folders)
  - Freedom Library Shelf, Rye Junior High School, Rye, N.H., 1963
  - Freedom of the press, 1951, 1958-1961, 1969-1971, undated
  - Freedom Press, 1958-1963, undated
  - Freedom School, Colorado Springs, Colo., 1957-1963 (Box 103)
  - Freedom Studies Center, Boston, Va., 1966, undated
  - Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge, Valley Forge, Pa., 1953-1974, undated, (2 folders)
  - Freeman Institute, 1981
  - Freemasons, 1956-1979, 1990-1993, undated, (3 folders)
  - Fresh Air Fund, 1952-1955
  - Friedan, Betty, 1970-1971
  - Friedheim, Robert, 1955-1960, undated For additional material see Container 17, Television, Correspondence
  - Friedman, Max, 1967-1971, undated
  - Friends of Fighters for Russian Freedom, 1951
  - Fritchman, Stephan H., 1953-1954, undated
  - Fuellhart, Ann, 1961-1963, undated (Box 104)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1958-1981, undated, (6 folders)
  - Fulbright, Newton H., 1952, 1959-1968, undated
  - Fuller, Peter, 1963-1965, 1991
  - Fund for the Republic, 1955-1959, undated, (3 folders) (Box 105)
  - Fund-raising, undated
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1849, 1939, 1949-1975, 1981-1991, undated, (3 folders)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1967-1968, undated
  - Galindez, Jesus de, 1956-1960, undated
  - Gangsters and gangsterism, 1959-1967, undated
  - Gardiner, John P., 1960, 1972
  - Gardner, James, 1961, undated
  - Garutso, Stephen E., 1957-1960
  - Gates, John, 1949, 1955-1958, 1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 106)
  - Geiger, Theodore S., undated
  - General Communications Corp., 1966-1967, undated
  - General Motors, 1970
  - Genocide, 1951-1956, 1971
  - Genovese, Eugene D., 1965-1973
  - Georgescu, V. C., 1953
  - Germany, 1949-1971, 1981-1988, undated, (5 folders)
  - Gessell, Gerhard A., 1970-1971 (Box 107)
  - Gezork, Herbert A., 1952-1964
  - Ghana, 1963-1972, undated
  - Giap, Vo Nguyen, 1968-1972, undated
  - Gill, William J., 1967, 1974-1979, undated
  - Ginzberg, Benjamin, 1969
  - Ginzberg, Ralph, 1964-1966
  - Gockenbach, Harold C. (“Pete”), 1964-1967, undated
  - Goff, Oliver Kenneth, 1962-1964, 1991
  - Gold, Harry, 1956, 1966
  - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1960-1967, undated
  - Goldfine, Bernard, 1960-1962
  - Goldwater, Barry M., 1960-1979, undated, (6 folders)
  - Goncharoff, Nicholas T., 1955-1956 (Box 108)
  - Goodwin, R. Dean, 1952-1967
  - Gordienko, Ruth, 1965-1972
  - Gordon, Rosalie M., 1957-1967
  - Gore, Albert (1907-1998), 1960-1971, undated, (2 folders)
  - Gottlieb, Richard, 1962
  - Gould, Kenneth M., 1952-1957, undated
  - Graham, Billy, 1957-1982, undated
  - Graham, Dean L., 1963-1964
  - Graham, Douglass R., 1956-1957
  - Grandin, Hartley T., 1964-1967
  - Gray, Edward S., 1955-1956
  - Great Britain, 1957, 1963, undated
  - Great Society, 1966-1967
  - Greece, 1967-1971, 1987, undated
  - Green, Gil, 1935, 1951, 1969
  - Green, Montgomery M., 1953-1956
  - Green Berets, 1969-1970
  - Greene, Felix, 1965-1966 (Box 109)
  - Greene, Janet, 1965-1968, undated
  - Gregory, Dick, 1968-1969, undated
  - Griffin, John, 1943, 1952-1953, undated
  - Groppi, James, 1967-1970, undated
  - Gross, Ernest A., 1959-1965, undated
  - Group Research, Inc., 1963-1965
  - Grundfest, Harry, 1952
  - Guatemala, 1957-1958, 1970
  - Guevara, Ernesto (“Che”), 1962-1969
  - Gun control laws, 1957, 1964-1972, undated
  - Guterma, Alexander L., 1959-1961, undated
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1948-1978, 1987-1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - Hadley, Otis N., 1956-1971
  - Haines, Ralph, 1972
  - Hairenik Weekly, 1961-1969
  - Haiti, 1965-1973
  - Hall, Gordon D., 1952-1972
  - Hall, Gus, 1951, 1964-1969, 1987-1990, undated
  - Hall, Rosamund C., 1960
  - Halperin, Maurice, 1953-1954, 1960
  - Halverson, Richard C., 1957-1969
  - Hamilton, Natalie Wales, 1959-1972
  - Hammer, Armand, 1970-1974, 1990
  - Hanson, Constance L., 1957 (Box 110)
  - Harding College, Searcy, Ark., 1951-1970, undated, (3 folders)
  - Hargis, Billy James, 1962-1972, undated
  - Hargroves, V. Carney, 1954-1959, undated
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 1959-1967
  - Harrington, Donald S., 1952-1963
  - Harrington, Michael, 1964-1972, undated
  - Harris, Fred R., 1966-1975
  - Harris, Stephen R., 1971-1984, undated
  - Hart, Merwin K., 1948-1966
  - Hartley, Fred A., 1959
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1953-1964, undated
  - Harvey, Paul, 1960-1962, 1968-1970, undated
  - Harvey, Richard, 1963-1971
  - Harwood, Clifford B., 1959-1975, undated
  - Hate groups and literature, 1951, 1959-1960, 1976, undated (Box 111)
  - Hawaii, 1955-1971, undated, (6 folders)
  - Hayden, Tom, 1968-1973, 1981, undated
  - Head, David C., 1962-1971, undated
  - Healey, Dorothy, 1960-1969
  - Health, Education, and Welfare Department, 1959-1961, 1967-1971, undated
  - Heilbronner, Hans, 1958-1959 (Box 112)
  - Helms, Jesse, 1967-1970, 1976-1978, undated
  - Henry C. Frick Educational Commission, 1964-1966
  - Herald of Freedom, 1969-1971
  - Herb Philbrick's Store, Rye Beach, N.H., 1954-1963, undated
  - Herschensohn, Bruce, 1972, undated
  - Herter, Christian Archibald, 1956-1959
  - Hess, Karl, 1967-1969
  - Hess, Rudolf, 1969-1971
  - Hester, Hugh B., 1959-1962
  - Hickel, Walter J., 1969-1970, undated
  - Higgins, Lloyd, 1949-1957
  - Highlander Folk School, Monteagle, Tenn., 1957-1965, undated
  - Hightower, John M., 1968, 1990, undated
  - Hill, Robert C., 1962-1971
  - Hill, Ross, 1970
  - Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Mich., 1979-1993, (2 folders)
  - Hilsman, Roger, 1964-1965
  - Hinson, W. M., 1963-1966
  - Hinton, William Howard, 1956-1957, 1969, undated
  - Hiss, Alger, 1949-1980, 1992, undated, (2 folders)
  - Hitler, Adolph, 1959, 1969-1970, undated (Box 113)
  - Ho Chi Minh, 1964-1973, undated
  - Hobson, Julius, 1969
  - Hoffa, James R., 1958-1963, 1973
  - Hoffman, Nicholas von, 1969-1971
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 1948, 1956, undated
  - Holland, Kenneth, 1959, undated
  - Hollywood
    - Miscellany, 1952, 1961-1968, undated
    - Reds in Hollywood, 1947-1964, 1985
  - Holtzhausser, Mae Elizabeth, 1961
  - Homans, William P., 1957-1958
  - Homosexuality, 1964, 1970-1993
  - Honrighausen, Elmer George, 1958, undated
  - Hood, Otis Archer, 1954-1959, 1972, undated
  - Hook, Sidney, 1972-1973
  - Hoover Institution, Stanford University, Stanford, Calif., 1968-1970, undated
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC), 1951-1969, undated, (3 folders)
  - Housing, 1957, 1966
  - Howard, Richard E., 1964-1967
  - Howard School for Girls, Bridgewater, Mass., 1960-1962
  - Howe, William, 1980-1981, undated
  - Howells, John N. M., 1954, 1962, undated
  - Hromadka, J. L., 1955-1959, undated
  - Hruby, Blahoslav S., 1968-1972, undated See also Containers 145-146, National Council of Churches (Box 114)
  - Hughes, Emmet John, 1964-1966
  - Hughes, H. Stuart, 1962, undated
  - Human Events, 1957-1975, undated, (4 folders)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio, 1957-1970, undated
  - Humphreys, Cecil Charles, 1959-1960
  - Hundred Club of New Hampshire, 1967-1969, 1983
  - Hungarian Freedom Fighters Federation, 1959, 1967-1970
  - Hungarian National Council, 1952-1957
  - Hungary, 1949-1990, undated, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 115)
  - Hunger, 1969-1971
  - Hunt, H. L., 1964-1972
  - Hunter, Edward
    - General, 1952-1978, undated, (2 folders)
    - Tactics, 1964-1977, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 116)
  - Huot, J. Oliva, 1966
  - Huss, Walter, 1960-1965
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 1949-1965, undated
  - Hyde, Arthur M., 1935-1936
  - Hyde, Homer H., 1960, undated
  - “H” miscellaneous, 1952-1976, 1986-1993, undated, (3 folders)
  - Immigration, 1956-1957, 1965-1967, 1984, undated
  - Income, 1968-1971
  - Independence Foundation, 1956-1958, (2 folders)
  - Independent American, 1958-1961, 1968, (2 folders) (Box 117)
  - Independent Food and Grocers Association of New Hampshire, 1955-1957
  - India, 1959-1971, 1978
  - Indiana, 1955-1961, undated
  - Indianapolis News, 1959-1964, undated
  - Indonesia, 1957-1970, undated
  - Industrial Workers of the World, 1956, 1962, 1969
  - Inflation, 1957, undated
  - Information Council of the Americas (INCA), 1961-1971
  - Ingwalson, Kenneth W., 1965-1967, undated
  - Institute for American Democracy, 1967-1969, undated
  - Institute for American Strategy, 1973-1974
  - Institute for Economic Inquiry, 1963-1964, undated
  - Institute for the Study of the USSR, 1957-1967, undated
  - Institute of Contemporary Russian Studies, Fordham University, New York, N. Y., 1953-1954, undated
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (IPR), 1951-1959 (Box 118)
  - Insurance rackets, 1954-1958, undated
  - Intelligence Digest, 1969-1972
  - Inter-National University Foundation, 1954-1955, undated
  - Intercollegiate Society of Individualists, 1961-1964, undated
  - Interfraternity Research and Advisory Council, 1954
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1954, 1967-1974, undated
  - Internal security, 1955-1957, 1980, undated
  - International Association for the Advancement of Ethnology and Eugenics (IAAEE), 1960-1964, undated
  - International Christian Leadership, 1956-1960, undated
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions, 1953-1957, undated, (2 folders)
  - International Council of Christian Churches, 1956-1965, 1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 119)
  - International Documentation and Information Centre (INTERDOC), 1967-1969
  - International Federation for Victory Over Communism, 1971
  - International Fur and Leather Workers Union, 1955, undated
  - International Peasant Union, 1956-1969, (2 folders)
  - International Rescue Committee, 1965, undated
  - International Research on Communist Techniques, 1956-1962, undated
  - International Services of Information Foundation, 1960-1964
  - International Union of Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (IUE), 1950-1953, undated
  - International Workers Order (IWO), 1948, 1955, undated
  - International Youth Federation of Freedom, 1964-1967, undated (Box 120)
  - Investments, 1953-1954, undated
  - Iowa Tests, 1957
  - Iran, 1971-1981, 1989, undated
  - Iraqi reds, 1958-1960
  - Ireland, 1969-1976
  - Irvine, Reed J., 1967-1977, 1985, undated
  - Israel, 1959-1974, undated
  - Italy, 1959-1976
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1948-1973, undated, (2 folders)
  - Jackson, Donald L., 1954-1963
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1959, 1970-1974, undated
  - Jackson, James E., 1951-1969, undated
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1971, undated
  - Jagan, Cheddi, 1961-1964, undated
  - Japan, 1960, 1970-1972, undated
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1959-1969
  - Jefferson Educational Foundation, 1968-1970, undated
  - Jefferson School of Social Sciences, New York, N. Y., 1949-1954, undated
  - Jewish Week, 1968-1969
  - Jews, 1948, 1956-1971, 1987, undated
  - Job Corps, 1965-1967 (Box 121)
  - John Birch Society, 1959-1979, undated, (10 folders)
  - Johnson, David, 1962
  - Johnson, Hewlett, “Red Dean” of Canterbury, 1948-1952, 1966, undated
  - Johnson, James E. (“Johnny”), 1974 (Box 122)
  - Johnson, Laurence A., 1954-1958, undated
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1959-1971, undated
  - Johnson, Manning, 1953, 1959-1964, undated
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, 1950-1955, undated
  - Jones, Jenkin Lloyd, 1962, 1971
  - Jonestown, Guyana, 1978-1979
  - Jordan, George Racey, 1956-1957, undated
  - Judd, Walter H., 1949, 1959-1972, undated
  - Justice Department, 1951-1973, 1991, undated, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 123)
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1951-1976, 1993, undated, (2 folders)
  - Kahn, Albert E., 1948, undated
  - Kalish, Abraham H., 1967-1992, undated, (2 folders)
  - Kamin, Leon J., 1955, undated
  - Kashnakheyev, Alexandr Yurievich, 1959-1960
  - Katzenbach, Nicholas deB., 1966, undated
  - Kaub, Verne P., 1953, undated
  - Kaufman, Miriam, 1944-1948
  - Kazan-Komarek, Vladimir, 1966-1967, undated
  - Keating, Kenneth B., 1961
  - Kempton, Murray, 1953 (Box 124)
  - Kennan, George Frost, 1966-1970, 1987, undated
  - Kennedy, Edward M., 1963-1982, 1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - Kennedy, Gerald, 1956, undated
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1960-1970, undated
  - Kennedy, John F., 1951, 1959-1977, 1992, undated, (3 folders)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., 1960-1972, undated
  - Kenney, Marie, 1947-1954
  - Kent State University, Kent, Ohio, 1970-1975, undated
  - Kerschner, Howard E., 1959-1968, undated (Box 125)
  - Key Records, 1964-1966, undated
  - Keys, Douglas, 1965-1972, undated
  - Khrushchev, Nikita, 1956-1974, undated, (6 folders)
  - Kim, David S. C., 1971
  - Kimball, Edwin H., 1957-1962 (Box 126)
  - King, Harry O., 1959
  - King, John W., 1963-1964
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr., (1929-1968), 1959-1972, undated, (3 folders)
  - Kingsbery, Emily, 1956-1963
  - Kingsbury, John A., 1952-1956, undated
  - Kissinger, Henry A., 1969-1979
  - Kizer, Benjamin H., 1939, 1946-1952
  - Klefos, Brede S., 1959, undated
  - Klein, Julius, 1958-1966
  - Kleindienst, Richard G., 1969-1970
  - Knott, Walter, 1962-1971, undated
  - Know your enemy, 1948, 1961, undated
  - Knowles, Mary, 1955-1960, undated
  - Koch, Leo F., 1960
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1951-1960
  - Kolasky, John, 1968 (Box 127)
  - Korea, 1953-1976, undated, (2 folders)
  - Kornfeder, Joseph Zack, undated
  - Kostka, William, 1953-1957
  - Kosygin, Alexei, 1965-1968, undated
  - Kozlov, Frol R., 1959, undated
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1965-1972, undated
  - Kuchel, Thomas H., 1963-1965, undated
  - Kunstler, William H., 1965-1970
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1949-1976, 1982-1986, undated
  - Labin, Suzanne, 1962-1972, undated
  - Labor, 1949-1968, 1981, undated
  - Labor Committee to Release Trade Unionists and Democratic Socialists, 1956, undated
  - Lady Chatterley's Lover, 1958-1959
  - Laird, Melvin R., 1969
  - Lamont, Corliss, 1952-1955, 1964-1967, undated
  - Lang, Edward R., 1963-1964
  - Laos, 1959-1971, undated
  - Lasky, Victor, 1953-1958, 1965, undated
  - Latimer, Ira H., 1967-1969, undated
  - Latin America, 1958-1971, 1983, undated (Box 128)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1950-1954, 1960-1974, 1989, undated
  - Latvia, 1952-1974, undated, (2 folders)
  - Lautner, John, 1959-1967, undated
  - Law enforcement, 1968
  - Lawrence, David, 1954, 1963-1967, undated
  - Lawrence, Robert G., 1953-1956
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1954, 1966
  - League for Justice, 1952-1953
  - League of Women Voters, 1954-1960, 1967-1969, undated
  - League to Uphold Congregational Principles, 1959
  - Leavy, William H., 1952-1958, undated
  - Lee, Joseph, 1959-1960
  - Lee, Robert (Sgt.), 1957-1960
  - Legislative Research, Inc., 1961-1962
  - Lehmann, Paul L., 1953-1954
  - Leibowitz, Samuel S., undated
  - Leka I, King of Albania, 1968-1971, undated
  - Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich, 1940, 1959-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 129)
  - Lerner, Max, 1952-1953, undated
  - Letter from Brussels ’58, 1958
  - Levinthal, Sonia, 1952, 1966-1967, undated
  - Levitas, S. M., 1956
  - Lewis, Frederick H. (“Bud”), 1954, undated
  - Lewis, Fulton (1903-1966), 1953-1966, undated
  - Lewis, Fulton (1933- ), 1967-1970, undated
  - Lewis, Marx, 1966-1977
  - Leyasmeyer, Karlis, undated
  - Liberal Citizens of Massachusetts, 1952-1964, undated
  - Liberty Amendment Committee of the USA, 1963-1970, undated
  - Liberty Lobby, 1961-1975, undated
  - Library of Congress, 1967-1970, 1987-1993, undated (Box 130)
  - Lieberman, Salomon (“Sali”), 1946, 1953, 1963, 1972-1974, undated
  - Life Line, 1963-1965, 1971-1972, undated
  - Life, 1961-1965, undated
  - Lightfoot, Claude, 1961, 1967-1969, undated
  - Lilly Endowment, 1967-1969
  - Lin Piao, 1965-1969
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1959, undated
  - Lincoln, Murray D., 1962-1963, undated
  - Lincoln-Petkov Academy (proposed), undated
  - Lindner, Robert, undated
  - Lindsay, John V., 1965-1970, undated, (1 folder) (Box 131)
  - Lions Club, Rye, N.H., 1958-1968, 1982, undated
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1958-1968
  - Lists of important people, 1953-1964, undated
  - Lithuania, 1955-1958, 1965, 1972, undated
  - Littell, Franklin H., 1966-1967
  - Little Boars Head, N.H., 1956-1958, undated
  - Liturgical Conference, 1968
  - Lively, Earl, 1964-1966, undated For additional material see Containers 223-226, “The Strange Death of President Kennedy”
  - Lobbying, 1970-1971, 1977
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1902-1985), 1960, 1969, undated
  - Loeffler, Ted, 1965-1969, undated
  - London, Charles N., 1965-1969 (Box 132)
  - Lone Star Steel Co., 1960, undated
  - Look, 1948, 1961-1969, undated
  - Lorch, Grace Lonergan, 1957-1958, undated
  - Lord, Sterling, 1956-1966, undated
  - Lothrop, Donald G., 1941, 1948-1963, undated
  - Louisiana Joint Legislative Committee on Un-American Activities, 1961, undated
  - Lowman, Meyers G., 1957-1966, undated
  - Loyalty oaths, 1950-1951, 1959-1968, undated
  - Loyola College, Baltimore, Md., 1951-1954
  - Lucas, Jim G., 1968-1970
  - Luce, Phillip Abbott, 1968-1972, undated
  - Lucom, Wilson C., 1967-1972, 1980, 1992, undated For additional material see Container 197, same heading
  - Lukens, Donald E. (“Buz”), 1969-1970, undated
  - Luscomb, Florence H., 1953-1955, undated
  - Lutheran Church, 1963-1965, 1972-1976
  - Luxemburg, Rosa, 1959, 1969
  - Lynd, Staughton, 1965-1969, undated
  - Lyons, Daniel, 1965-1971, undated
  - Lyons, Eugene, 1955-1967, undated (Box 133)
  - Lyttle, Bradford, 1967, undated
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1952-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1954, 1963-1976, undated
  - MacBride, Roger, 1963-1970, undated
  - MacCarthy, Shane, 1956-1957, undated
  - Macedonian Tribune, 1969-1973, undated
  - MacKay, John A., 1953-1954
  - MacKenzie, H. E., 1956
  - Macmillan, Harold, 1959
  - Mafia, 1961, 1969-1972, undated
  - Maher, Albert, 1964
  - Mailing lists, 1952-1954, 1967-1970, undated
  - Maltz, Albert, 1960
  - Manchester Union Leader, 1956-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 134)
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1953-1971, undated
  - Manion, Clarence E., 1954-1976, undated, (4 folders)
  - Mann, Roger W., 1960-1964
  - Manson, Charles, 1969-1970, undated
  - Mao Tse-Tung, 1953-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box 135)
  - Marble Collegiate Church, New York, N. Y., 1956-1958, undated
  - Marcus, J. Anthony, 1958-1961
  - Marcuse, Herbert, 1968-1970
  - Markham, Helen Wendler Deane, 1953, 1966, undated
  - Markward, Mary, 1951-1956
  - Martin, David, 1965-1971, undated
  - Martz, Glenn, 1958-1959, 1966
  - Marx, Groucho, 1957
  - Marzani, Carl, 1961, 1969
  - Masaryk, Thomas G., 1960
  - Mass media, 1968-1971, undated
  - Massachusetts Commission on Communism, Subversive Activities, and Related Matters, 1950-1958, undated
  - Massachusetts Political Action for Peace (PAX), 1960-1970, undated